Guide to the Harry Gamboa Jr. Papers, 1968-1995
Department of Special Collections
Harry Gamboa Jr. Papers,
1968-1995
Special Collections M0753
Harry Gamboa Jr.
10 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
Do not reproduce photograph of Cyclona.
Do not duplicate, broadcast, or computer transmit the following audio tape recordings:
Audiotape #3, Side A, Program "a"; Telephone conversation: Willie Herron.
Audiotape #3, Side B, Programs "bb, cc, dd"; Music by the Undertakers.
Audiotape #2, Side B, Program "c"; TV show broadcast Let's Rap.
Audiotape #9, Side A, Program "g"; Music by The Brat.
Do not duplicate, broadcast, or computer transmit the following video tape recordings:
Videotape #1, Program "e"; "FIRE MEDICINE"
Videotape #11, Program "b"; "IGNORE THE DENTS"
Provenance:
Purchased from the artist, 1995
BIOGRAPHY
Harry Gamboa Jr. was born in 1951, the first of five children born to Harry T. Gamboa and Carmen Gamboa, a working class Mexican American couple. He grew up in East Los Angeles California, an urban area tormented by poverty, violence and racial conflict. Despite these surroundings, the inadequacy of the East L.A. public schools and his parents' lack of education, Gamboa was encouraged to value education and did fairly well in school. As a teenager he was active in community organizations and politics. As a student at High School (graduated 1969) Gamboa was active in student government and as an organizer of various student-initiated reforms, most significantly the 1968 "East L.A. Blowouts" -a series of protests against the inferior conditions of public schools in poor, non-white areas.
Gamboa's extra-curricular activities were not, however, limited to politics. Already a developing artist, it was at Garfield High that Gamboa met Gronk (Glugio Nicondra), Patssi (then Patsy) Valdez and Willie Herrón, three of his closest associates in his later career. After the "Blowouts," for his final year of high school, Gamboa dropped out of the political scene in order to dedicate himself to his education. Thanks to these efforts and with the help of the Equal Opportunities Program (EOP) for disadvantaged minority students, Gamboa was able to attend California State University at Los Angeles. From this point his career as an artist -both solo and with Gronk, Valdez and Herrón in the art collective ASCO (Spanish for nausea)-took off.
Gamboa's work as a writer, photographer, film-maker, performance artist and multi-media creator of "things" is diverse, but in all his efforts (including those as a member of ASCO) his focus has been to reveal the absurdity of urban life and to confront both the dominant white culture and various perspectives within Chicano culture, pointing to the pain and alienation caused by both. This is often achieved by altering the media of the art itself, as opposed to just the subject matter. Gamboa's most significant works include mail art of the 1970s, ASCO's "no movies," the "urban opera" Ignore the Dents and Jetter's Jinx.
Gamboa has one son, Diego, born c. 1980, a product of his first marriage. In 1993 Gamboa married his second wife, Chicano muralist Barbara Carrasco, after seven years of romantic and professional involvement. Their daughter, Barbara Gamboa, was born in 1994.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
This collection of 8.5 linear feet (10 manuscript boxes, 1 half-sized manuscript box, 4 print boxes and 2 map case folders) of papers and items relating to the career of L.A.-based Chicano artist Harry Gamboa Jr. was purchased from the artist by Stanford University in 1995. The collection includes various materials dating from 1968 to 1995 and covering a broad range of Gamboa's personal and professional life. More than forty original manuscripts, both published and unpublished, produced and unproduced, represent Gamboa's work as a writer of fiction, prose, film, television, theater and performance scripts, interviews and essays. Manuscripts include "Jetter's Jinx," "Ignore the Dents" and many lesser known works. The collection also contains rare copies of Gamboa's mail art of the 1970s and other original art and miscellaneous (original drawings, art lay-out boards, buttons designed by Gamboa, etc.). Nine audio cassettes and thirteen video cassettes contain Gamboa and ASCO performances, productions and interviews, and more than 250 slides provide visual images of Gamboa's work in several media. Exhibition materials (fliers, posters, etc.), catalogues, and brochures document Gamboa and exhibitions and performances. Other publications (including various Chicano art/culture journals such as Raza Art and Media Collective, Regeneracíon, Caminos, Chismearte, and Neworld) contain artwork, photography and writing by Gamboa, as well as interviews and articles relating to Gamboa's work and that of other Chicano artists. Various publications, articles, and clippings discuss Los Angeles Chicano Civil Rights activities of the 1960s and '70s, in particular El Chicano Moratorium and the Garfield High School "Blowout" protests in which Gamboa was a key figure.
Further insight into the context in which Gamboa is working can be found in his primarily incoming personal and professional correspondence, largely with other Chicano artists. Correspondence includes letters relating to the break up of in 1987, to Gamboa's fallout with friend and collaborator Daniel J. Martinez, and other events of Gamboa's career. Notable correspondents include members Gronk, Patssi Valdez, Humberto Sandoval, and Willie Herrón, Gamboa's wife, Barbara Carrasco, and sister, Diane Gamboa, as well as numerous friends and associates: Carlos Almarez, Max Benavidez, Robert Buitrón, Ralph Cordova, Frances Salomé España, Ramón Favela, Shifra Goldman, Ricardo Gonzales, Magu Lujan, Marcos Sanchez and Holly Barnet-Sanchez, Ruben Trejo, Jesús Salvador Treviño, John Valadez, Willie Varela, and Zaneta and Zaragosa Vargas. The collection also contains correspondence relating to Gamboa's activities within the Los Angeles Chicano community and to a graduate art seminar taught by Gamboa at Cal Arts. Various photographs and clippings are included in the correspondence. In short, the wide range of materials included in the collection provide a detailed summary of Harry Gamboa Jr.'s work as an artist and the social context within which he is working.
A separate Stanford collection (Photo 177) of .25 linear feet contains 44 original Gamboa photographs, one set of photocopy duplicates and one folder of biographical information.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Original Manuscripts by Gamboa
  - "100 Alibis" 19941 of 2. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "100 Alibis", 19942 of 2: original text art from "The Urban Desert" exhibition. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Alibi No" 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Antizona" 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Ashes to Ashes, Smog to Smog" 1992"Baby Kake" 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Bravo Heights" 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Chaka L.A. CA" 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Chicano Art in L.A." n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Cold Java" 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Club Limbo" 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Exit Rey" 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Hate Male" 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Head's Turn" 1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Hiss Panic and Other Poems" 1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "I Don't Buy My Tacos from Trucks Parked Too Close to Sex Change Clinics" 1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Ignore the Dents", "Double Negativity" and "Asphalt" 1990produced together. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "In the Realm of the Senseless" 1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Ismania" 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Jetter's Jinx" 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Kiko's Hut" 1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Light at the End of Tunnel Vision" 1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "No Alibi" 1991 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "No Beans in My Tortilla" 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "No Crossing" 1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "No Supper" 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Off Lines" 1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Orphans of Modernism" 1984Acts I and II. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Oscar's Middle Finger" 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Past Imperfecto" 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Pinguino" 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Refractions of Home" 1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Rush Hour" 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Shadow Solo" 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Urban Exile" 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Vaporz" 1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Vex Requiem" 19891 of 3: description of scenes/outline. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Vex Requiem", 19892 of 3: 1st draft. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Vex Requiem", 19903 of 3: unfinished 2nd draft; final draft. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Void and Vain" 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Where They Found Javier" 1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Whichever Way the Lead Blows" 1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Writer's Blockade" 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Series II: Photocopied Manuscripts by Gamboa
  - "Cafe O'Lay" 1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Chavalo Was Lost at Sí" 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Focus on the Invisible" 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Lorena's Lament" c. 1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Vacant Tour" 1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Original mail art 1975-1977by Gamboa: "Artopsy", "Dia de los Muertos", "Autologue I", "Autologue II", "Young Boy in the 50s !", "Young Buy in the 50s II", "Red Gun 40/130"; "90 Proof Loaf" 1984postcard by Gamboa. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Original text art by Gamboa used to produce fliers. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Original text art by Gamboa used to produce fliers, for "Connections 2"exhibit. (Box 2)
  - Original notes: Gamboa 1988-1995Barbara Carrasco 1992 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence regarding grant applications/awards/rejections 1980-1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - East Los Angeles walkouts and related miscellaneous/Garfield High School c. 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Series III: Gamboa/ASCO exhibition materials
  - Gamboa/ASCO exhibition materials, 1 of 7: A-Ar 1972-1994 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Gamboa/ASCO exhibition materials, 2of 7: ASCO 1974-1985 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Gamboa/ASCO exhibition materials, 3 of 7: B-F 1975-1994 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Gamboa/ASCO exhibition materials, 4 of 7: Gamboa 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Gamboa/ASCO exhibition materials, 5 of 7: H-J 1983-1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gamboa/ASCO exhibition materials, 6 of 7: L-P 1975-1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Gamboa/ASCO exhibition materials, 7 of 7: R-W 1973-1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gamboa/ASCO miscellaneous, 1 of 3: (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Benavídez/Vozoff, "The Wall: Image and Boundary, Chicano Art in the 1970s" 1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "A Biennial Scorecard" 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Brookman,A./Brookman, P., "Mi Otro Yo-My Other Self" 1986documentary transcript (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Danmarks Radio: "Hispanics in the U.S.A." 1984radio transcriptGamboa, "Taking People to the Wall in Mesa" 1984"Exilio Urbano" in La Opinion"Urban Exile" in Newsweek1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Hollander, "Iluminando Fronteras" 1994in Poliester (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Noriega, "Talking Heads, Body Politic" 1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Sanchez/Barnet-Sanches: "Chicano Murals: Cultural Representation of and American Community" n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Gamboa/ASCO miscellaneous, 2 of 3: reviews 1973-1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Gamboa/ASCO miscellaneous, 3 of 3: clippings 1978-1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - CARA Chicano Art-Resistance and Affirmation/ASCO video project, 1 of 3: video proposal and essay by Gamboa c. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - CARA Chicano Art-Resistance and Affirmation/ASCO video project, 2 of 3: pamphlets/correspondence c. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - CARA Chicano Art-Resistance and Affirmation/ASCO video project, 3 of 3: photographs 1974, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gamboa at Cal Arts, 1 of 3: miscellaneous student work and correspondence 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Gamboa at Cal Arts, 2 of 3: Dirk Westphal, work/correspondence 1989-1993CAUTION: Folder contains SHARP-EDGED metal sheet art. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Gamboa at Cal Arts, 3 of 3: photographs 1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Series IV: General Correspondence
  - Almaraz, Carlos 1982-1993including artist profile by Gamboa. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Arteaga, Alfred n.d., 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Avalos, David 1985-c. 1994including copies of work. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Benavídez, Max 1984-1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Buitrón, Robert 1983-1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Carrasco, Barbara, 1 of 3: reproductions of work, exhibition materials 1985-1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Carrasco, Barbara, 2 of 3: artist profile by Gamboa n.d.clippings 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Carrasco, Barbara, 3 of 3: correspondence and photos 1985-1995 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Carrillo, Sean, 1 of 2: correspondence 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Carrillo, Sean, 2 of 2: color Xerox photo notebook from "Gamboa 82" exhibit, "Brown in Black and White" 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cordova, Ralph n.d., 1982-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cristeto, Armando 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cyclona 1993-1994[RESTRICTION: Do not reproduce photo of CYCLONA]. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - España, Frances Salome 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Favela, Ramon 1987-1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fusco, Coco 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Gamboa, Diane 1983-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gamboa, Diego 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gamboa, Harry T. and Carmen n.d., 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gamboa outgoing correspondence: (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Memo to ASCO members regarding ASCO break-up 3/31/87 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fax correspondence 1990, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Garcia, Lorraine 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Garcia, Willie 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Garza, Juan 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Goldman, Shifra 1990-1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Gonzales, Ricardo n.d., 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Gronk Glugio Nicondra (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Guglielmo, Rudy n.d., 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Herrera, Juan Felipe 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Juárez, Miguel 1992 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Limon, Leo 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lujan, Magu 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Marchand, Arthur 1980-1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Martinez, Daniel J. 1984-1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Medina, Joe n.d., 1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Montoya, Richard 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Museum of Modern Art, New York 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Navarro, Raymond 1990 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Olsen, Mark 1988-1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Rascón, Armando n.d., 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Rodriguez, Eloy n.d., 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Rosas, Alejandro 1986-1991Salazar, Rick 1992-1994Sanchez, Marcos and Holly Barnet-Sanchez 1986-1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sandoval, Humberto n.d., 1982Sandoval, Sandra 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Trejo, Ruben 1990-1991Treviño, Jesús Salvador n.d., 1987-1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Valadez, John 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Valdez, Patssi n.d., 1978-1986 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Valverde, Ricardo 1981-1983photographs of Gamboa. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Varela, Willie 1992-1995Vargas, Jack 1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Vargas, Apolina 1991-1993Zaneta 1985-1994Zaragosa 1971-1993 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Velazquez, Gerardo 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Villa, Raul n.d., 1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Villarreal, Danny 1987 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Viramontes, Helena Maria 1985-1992 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art 1995 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Yañez, René n.d., 1988-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Series V: Publications
  - 201 1982incl. "A Rival Departure" by Gamboa. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Actuel 7-8/87incl. article "Les Chicanos" with mention of Gamboa and associated Chicano artists. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Americas 2001 11-12/87cover photo of Dolores Huerta by Gamboa. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Ancient Roots, New Visions 1977-1979incl. "Tu Culpa, Mi Culpa" by Gamboa 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Art Forum Newsletter 11/84mentions Gamboa. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Art in America 9/80 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Art in America, 12/87 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Art in America, 6/92incl. article "Chicano Identities" with ASCO, other Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Art Press 8/90; 9/90; 10/90including Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Artes Visuales 6/81incl. Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Attitudes and Expressions, incl. photo of Harry and Diego Gamboa by Daniel J. Martinez. 11/84-1/85The Brat Songbook. ( Therese Covarrubias is the Brat) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Broken Line 5/86incl. quote from "Urban Exile" by Gamboa, other Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Caminos 3/80incl. photo essay "Day of the Focus" by Gamboa (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Caminos, 10/83including "ASCO 83" by Gamboa. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Cantos 1991poetry by Alfred Arteaga. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Chicanarte 1975incl. sculpture "Colonial Failure Kit" by Gamboa. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Chicano Codices 1992incl. "The Single Element" by Gamboa, work by other Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Chicano Expressions 1986incl. drawing "Assassin's Trace" by Gamboa; work by other Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Chismearte 1976incl. interview: Gamboa, Gronk ASCO (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Chismearte, 1984including "Shadow Solo" by Gamboa. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Connections 2 1994exhibit incl. "Echoes in the Impasse" by Gamboa. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cono Sur 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Contemporary Identites 1993incl. photos from "Chicano Male Unbonded" series by Gamboa. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Corazon de Aztlan 1-2/82incl. "No Gray Matter" by Gamboa. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Corazon de Aztlan, 3-4/82incl. "Ins and Outs" by Gamboa. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Counterweight 11/92-1/93including "Fire Medicine" video by Gamboa not pictured (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - De Colores: The Best of Chicano Fictions 1981incl. "Pseudotourquoisers" by Gamboa. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Education and the Mexican American Community 4/68 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Empowering Raza Youth Through the Arts II 1994incl. photos of students by Gamboa. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Festival Internacional de Video III1990catalogue and program, incl. "L.A. Merge" by Gamboa. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Forty Years of California Assemblage 1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Framework 1990incl. "Double Negativity" by Gamboa. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Framework, 1992incl. "Chavalo Was Lost at Sí" by Gamboa. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Grito del Sol 7-9/76incl. "Cruel Profit" by Gamboa. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hecho en Latinoamerica 1978incl. photos by Gamboa. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Hecho en Latinoamerica II 1981incl. photos by Gamboa. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Helter Skelter 1992incl. "Rush Hour" and "Low and Flow" by Gamboa, work by other Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - High Performance 1981incl. ASCO "No Phantoms", photos by Gamboa. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - High Performance, 1986including "Art with a Chicano Accent" article mentioning Gamboa, other Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - High Performance, 1989incl. "Social Afterimages" art seminar taught by Gamboa. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - High Performance, 1992incl. "Asphalt/Asfalto" poem by Gamboa. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hispanic Art in the United States 1987incl. Gamboa-associated artists, mentions Gamboa. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Hispanic Theatre in the United States and Puerto Rico 1988incl. Gamboa/ASCO. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Ignore the Dents 1990a "Micro Urban Opera" written by Gamboa. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Imagine 1986incl. "Urban Exile", "Zen Visibility" and "Belted Consent" by Gamboa. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Journal 1987incl. "The Chicano Artist Inside and Outside the Mainstream" by Gamboa. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Jumpcut 1994incl. "The No Movie Interview" re: ASCO, by Gronk and Gamboa. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - La Luz 10/77incl. "Film, Television and Treviño" by Gamboa, re: Jesus Salvador Treviño. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - La Raza 1971re: Chicano civil rights issues. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Los Angeles Contemporary Exhibitions LACE10 Years Documented 1987incl. Gamboa, others. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Los Angeles Exhibition LAX1994including Gamboa, Daniel J. Martinez. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - L.A. Hot and Cool 1988incl. Gamboa. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Los Angeles Theatre Center 9/85-5/86incl. ASCO. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Los Angeles Times Magazine 3/27/88incl. article "Born in East L.A." re: Chicano artists. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Made in Aztlan 1986incl. Gamboa, others. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - MALDEF 1980re: Mexican American Legal Defense Fund MALDEF (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Metamorfosis 1984-1985incl. "Urban Exile" by Gamboa. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Metaphor 1995incl. "L.A. Familia" by Gamboa. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Museum of Contemporary Art MOCAAuction 1994incl. photo "Patssi Valdez" by Gamboa. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Neworld 1976incl. "Gronk and Herrón" interview by Gamboa. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Neworld, 1980incl. "Gronk: Off-The-Wall Artist" interview by Gamboa. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Newsweek 2/3/92 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Off the Street 4-5/85incl. Gamboa, others. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - OMNI 2/91 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Oversight 1992incl. "Collapse of Memory" by Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Photography 3/79incl. article "The Mexican Americans." (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - El Playano 1972, 1973including work by Gamboa, other Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Police-Comunity Relationships in E.L.A., Calif. 1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Scratching the Belly of the Beast 1994incl. article "Ni de aquí, ni de allá: Latinos/as in the Imagination of Southern California" mentioning Gamboa/ASCO and "Baby Kake." (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Somos 6/79incl. "Film, Television, and Treviño" by Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Psychology Today 1-2/89 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Raza Art and Media Collective RAMC39/1/76incl. "Chicano Cinema: Autologue 25, 75 & 100" by Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - RAM Collective 6/1/77incl. "Cruel Profit" by Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Regeneración: vol. 1.6 1970re: death of Ruben Salazar (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Regeneración, vol. 1.8 1970incl. letter by Gamboa, cover lettering by Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Regeneración, vol 1.9 1970cover and various drawings by Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Regeneración, vol. 2.1 1971incl. various drawings by Gamboa, "Genocide Patrol" and "Another Day, Another Murder" by Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Regeneración, vol. 2.2 1971incl. various drawings by Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Regeneración, vol. 2.3 1971incl. various drawings by Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Regeneración, vol. 2.4 1971incl. various drawings by Gamboa, "Chismosa" by Gamboa, and ASCO advertisements. 2 copies, one autographed by various Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Sound Waves 1988WEA Manufacturing Inc. employee newsletter, incl. mention of employee Harry T. Gamboa's family of artists. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - The Stopping of Sorrow 1985by Max Benavidez. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Theatre Communications Group TCGInc., mentions "Vex Requiem" by Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - A Traves de la Frontera 1983catalogue incl. Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Visions: Winter 1989incl. Yañez article mentioning ASCO, etc. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Visions, Fall 1989"Acculturation and Assimilation" issue re: various Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Visions, Spring 1992incl. article re: Chicano-Latino artists. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Visions, Spring 1993incl. article re: Chicano-Latino artists. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - The Visual Statement 1991incl. Gamboa. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Xhismearte 1977incl. "Fade In" by Gamboa, work by other Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Xhismearte, 1980incl. "Wiping the Smiles" by Gamboa, work by other Gamboa-associated artists. (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Series VI: Oversized Publications, Newspapers.
  Most of the materials in this series include mention of Gamboa and/or Gamboa-associated artists
  - Afterimage 11-12/93 (Box 10)
  - Albuquerque Journal 2/28/92 (Box 10)